

J	(646) 592-2569
\square	joe@weel.dev
in	linkedin.com/in/joe-wee
(7)	github.com/JWeel

Forenote

Having been hiring manager, I know how many fake resumes are out there. Rest assured, this is a genuine resume belonging to a real person (me).

Profile

Highly skilled and motivated Software Engineer with 8 years of experience looking for a staff engineer, manager, or director role.

As manager, I have had the opportunity to grow multiple teams into efficient powerhouses delivering million-dollar revenue projects in limited time. I've successfully attracted, developed and retained engineering talent under my supervision.

As individual contributor, I've consistently demonstrated top performance. I have been described as a rising star, best mentor to work with, great teacher and leader, trusted to find what others missed, known for keeping performance and security at the forefront of all work, and having a proven track record of handling rapidly growing responsibilities.

I have proficiency with the following technologies: C#, .NET Framework, .NET Core, Sql Server, T-SQL, Angular, Python, gRPC, WCF, WPF, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, GitHub, Jira, REST, OAuth, Redis, RabbitMQ, Azure, Dynatrace, Hangfire, Docker, Figma, TestOps, Playwright

Experience

Software Engineering Manager

Viventium: 2024-present US Remote

Advanced from managing one team, to two, then to forming an entirely new team for a brand-new core product. Chosen to represent entire development department in cross-departmental projects. Split time between hands-on development and management.

- Led research, development, and deployment of three multimillion-dollar revenue software integrations in one quarter. Made critical architecture decisions on security and automation to facilitate scaling. Led discussions with partners and advised on their implementations.
- Building calculation engine that continuously processes payloads at high throughput in real-time. Overseeing coordination between different teams that hook into this project. Managing backend and frontend engineers building the supporting pieces.

Senior Software Engineer

Viventium: 2022-2023 US Remote

Full ownership of the development and design of web services, REST APIs, Azure functions, third party integrations, code generation tools, and much more. In charge of mentoring and management of junior developers. Consistently taking projects from start to finish, including gathering and writing of specs, programming, overseeing QA, and handling deployment.

- · Built webhook infrastructure allowing clients to subscribe to events, reducing load on open APIs previously used for monitoring.
- Designed and developed the business logic for transforming external file formats to an internal proprietary format, effectively eliminating the biggest time sink for clients when importing data. Supervised junior in building tools that leverage it.

Backend Software Engineer

Viventium: 2019-2021 New York, New York

 $Moved \ to \ New \ York \ in \ May \ 2019. \ Joined \ Viventium \ to \ work \ on \ their \ Payroll / HRIS \ software, specializing \ in \ third \ party \ integrations.$

- Redesigned mass data imports for better performance and maintainability, and enabling reverting imports. Massively reduced time spent by clients and support staff on payroll and demographic data, and enabled faster development of new imports.
- Implemented integration with tax compliance software, facilitating company expansion into all US states.
- Designed framework for creating background services and built several to handle internal processes and to synchronize internal data with external partners. This enabled company to rapidly integrate with new vendors, as development work became trivial.

Team Lead

2at: 2018-2019 Utrecht, Netherlands

Became team lead after one year to fill gap left by retiring leadership. Oversaw development of multinational web apps for clients.

- Led client communication with sprint demos, project planning, and project deployment. Praised for handling unexpected issues.
- Trained and supported junior developers and onboarded new senior developers. Led code review sessions and tech demos.

Software Developer

2at: 2017-2018 Utrecht, Netherlands

Joined this software consulting company to do full-stack development and design of custom apps, leveraging Microsoft technologies.

- Organized migration of SOAP services to REST APIs for consistent architecture and better maintainability and scalability.
- Configured CI/CD pipelines for legacy and new web applications, reducing deployment time by up to 95%.

Education

Personal Interests

University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, Netherlands Bachelor of Science in Artificial Intelligence: 2013-2016 Minor in Computer Science (Programming): 2015-2016

As husband and father, most of my free time is spent with family. When possible, I like working on software hobby projects, cooking, writing, or playing and watching basketball.